

Setsoto Hlohlomi

ADDRESS 1 : Ha Matala, Maseru Lesotho
ADDRESS 2 : Can relocate to Gauteng, South

Africa

VISA NUM: JNGSFCQ (Critical Skills Visa in IT)

PHONES: (+266)58565709
EMAIL: shlohlomi@gmail.com

CITIZENSHIP: MOSOTHO **GENDER**: FEMALE

LANGUAGES: ENGLISH, SESOTHO

Objectives

To pursue a challenging career and professional environment which encourages learning, where my knowledge can be shared and enriched for the growth of the organization and self and needing to relocate to South Africa due to family reasons

Profile

System Administrator with skills in Windows Server and Client Operating systems, Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, VMWare, SCCM, SQL, Software and Hardware support and some basic experience with Java Development. Resourceful with troubleshooting and problem solving skills obtained in the IT department with a BEng Degree in Computer Systems and Networks (NQF 8 by SAQA Evaluation)

LinkedIn : https://www.linkedin.com/in/setsoto-hlohlomi-450a7a75

Github : https://github.com/setsotohlohlomi
Website : https://setsotohlohlomi.github.io/
Twitter : https://twitter.com/christyhlohlomi

Skills Matrix

1. Had appropriate training only

2. Limited working experience

3. Solid practical experience

4. Well versed, extensive experience

5. Expert, extensive work experience

Skill Type/Technology	Skill Level	Years of	Last Used
		Experience	
Java core	2	1.0	2015
Java - android	2	1.0	2015
Java FX	2	0.5	2015
OOP	2	1.0	2015
HTML,Bootstrap,CSS	2	1.0	Current
Github	2	0.5	Current
Windows server (2003,2008,2012)	4	2.5	Current
Active Directory	4	2.0	Current
Group Policy	4	2.0	Current

Skill Type/Technology	Skill Level	Years of	Last Used
72 /		Experience	
DNS	4	2.0	Current
DHCP	4	2.0	Current
File services	4	2.0	Current
DFS Replication	3	1.5	Current
Print Services	4	2.0	Current
P C Hardware support(Removal, or	3	3.0	Current
RAM, HD, Monitors)			
MS Lync Client 2010,2013	3	2.0	Current
Skype for business client 2015	3	1.0	Current
MS SQL Server 2012	2	1.0	Current
BMC Remedy Incident	3	2.5	Current
Management			
Remote Desktop Services	3	1.0	Current
VMWare(Host Management)	3	1.5	Current
VMWare(VM Management)	3	1.5	Current
SCCM	3	1.0	Current
Unix Administration	1		
Microsoft Exchange Server	2	0.5	Current
Skype for Business Server	2	0.5	Current
Windows Client(7,8.1,10)	4	2.5	Current
MS Office(2010, 2013)	4	3.0	Current
Xerox and Konika Minolta Printer	3	2.0	Current
Support(Basic troubleshooting,			
toner replacement, paper jam			
removal)			
HP IRS server Hardware	3	1.5	Current
monitoring			

Employment History

Company : Vodacom Lesotho
Position : Specialist IT Operations
Date : June 2015 – Present

Duties :

- Installation and configuration of windows servers and client PCs
- Setting up SCCM architecture and administration of windows devices using SCCM
- Administration of active directory roles in the organization, Creation and modification of advanced group policy objects application compatibility, account security and organization standardization
- Configuration and management of DHCP scopes to be integrated with networking devices for allocation of IP addresses for LAN and Wireless access to the network
- Supporting Exchange Clients, Webmail and Skype for Business
- Managing the internal windows DNS server, creation of zones and diverse DNS entries as required by clients and the applications requiring resolution
- Management of the Virtual platform for both production and disaster recovery ESXi
 5.5 Hosts with Training in v6, Creation, Configuration, Cloning, Deletion (clean-up) of

- VMs and reconfiguration of ESXi hosts as required using VSphere, Liaise with Suppliers and Support for upgrades of ESXi Hosts when host resources have been depleted
- Setting up a geographically redundant architecture for Active directory, SMTP, File server, Print Server and System performance reporting
- Creation of a central storage for the organizations documents and configuring active directory authentication for secure access to folders on the file server, configuring DFS replication to synchronize changes to a backup server for redundancy, file screening and quota management
- Administering print servers which enable centralized printing, troubleshooting of printer models like Konica Minolta, HP and Xerox devices for basic error resolution and escalation to suppliers when necessary
- Support of software and hardware issues pertaining to client PCs. Basic part replacement, Hard drives and RAM, monitoring of Server Hardware using HP IRS for proactive notification of hardware failures to the Department and to HP

Company : Vodacom Lesotho
Position : Intern: Service desk
Date : Feb 2015 – May 2015

Duties :

- Technical support of windows client operating systems and basic hardware parts replacement
- Logging and tracking of incidents for clients
- Service desk reporting and analysis of improvement or discrepancy in resolution of incidents
- Follow up on client incidents to ensure satisfactory resolution of incidents

Company : National University of Lesotho

Position : Java Demonstrator Date : 2013(Sept - Nov)

Duties :

- Assisting students during labs during the course of the Java programming Language with exercises
- Clarification and tutoring for Java core concepts such as OOP, Classes, Functions and assisting with Database connections from Java – MySQL

Corporate Achievements

- ✓ Successfully deployed a single site System Centre Configuration Manager which I am currently using to upgrade client PCs to Windows 10, reporting and pushing of software's
- ✓ Successfully created a custom Windows 10 image with all the necessary software's in order to make deployment and configuration of windows clients easier
- ✓ Successful completion of user and mailbox migration from the local Vodacom active Directory domain to a global Vodafone domain for standardization
- ✓ Liaised with support for implementation of a new VMWare ESXi Host and migration VMs to the new Host

- ✓ Group policy remodelling to reinforce user accounts security using group policy objects and passwords conforming to minimum requirements
- ✓ Cost cutting on server hardware contracts by compiling an up to date corporate server inventory of existing commissioned servers
- ✓ Obtained best team award for organizing training and empowering first line technical support at retail stores which enabled faster resolution times for IT related incidents at Vodacom Lesotho
- ✓ Successful deployment of an Active Directory, File server and print server Disaster recovery server for geographical redundancy
- ✓ A Java application that helped in migration of user profiles to another global domain at Vodacom Lesotho by specifying a list of PC numbers and it would return a list of IP addresses of the PC's to a text file

Personal Achievements

- √ 4th and 1st Prize winner at the NUL HACKATHON 2013/2014 and
 2014/2015(respectively) all night programming competition sponsored by Vodacom
- ✓ Best student in computer systems and networks 2015 awarded by Econet Telecom Lesotho for being the best graduate in the course
- ✓ Best student in Cisco networking 2015 for being the best performing graduate in the Cisco Curriculum
- ✓ Best student in ICT 2015 for being the best ICT student
- ✓ Best female student in Cisco networking 2014 for being the best performing student in the Cisco Curriculum

Education				
Qualification	Institution	Duration		
Administering Windows Server	Microsoft	April 2017		
2012 (Exam 70411)				
Training for Configuring	Torque IT	Feb 2017		
Advanced Windows Server				
2012				
Microsoft Certified	Microsoft	July 2016		
Professional (Exam 70410)				
Training for VMWare v6,	HP Rovinia	June 2016		
Install, Configure and Manage				
Unix System Administration	Internet Society	Nov 2015		
Bachelor of Engineering in	The National University of	2010 - 2015		
Computer Systems and	Lesotho			
Networks (SAQA NQF 8)				
C.O.S.C (First Class, Top 4)	Ts'akholo High School	2008 - 2009		

Other projects

• Java Desktop Maze game – a simple windows application with several levels

- Java Desktop MAC address finder over Wi-Fi connection which tracks PC's with a mac addresses when connected to a Wi-Fi hotspot and won me 4th Place at the first NUL Hackathon
- Track My Droid(Java-Android) detects SIM change in a stolen phone and sends the new number to contacts specified before the theft, aiding in tracking by the authorities and won me first place in the second NUL hackathon
- Face Recognition and RFID Security System(final year project)

Personal Qualities and Interests

- Hard working and dedicated
- Quick and Constant learning and Resourceful
- · Good interpersonal and relational skills
- No supervision required and driven with passion
- Analytical and Social with good verbal and communication skills
- Travelling and learning new places
- Reading books(Motivational and Educational)

References

1. LEBAMANG MOHAI

Senior Manager: Core Networks, Vodacom Lesotho

Email: Lebamang.Mohai@vodacom.co.ls

Phone: +266 5221 2298

2. KOPANO MOEKETSI

Lecturer: National university of Lesotho

Email : fk.moeketsi@nul.ls
Phone : +266 5221 3514

3. MAMOTHOKOANE TLALI

Manager: LsNIC, Lesotho Communications Authority

Email : Mtlali@lca.org.ls
Phone : +2665 222 1300